<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<chapter id="sid-3735784">
    
    <title>Service Development</title>
    <para>
      Services can be developed by generating initial development artifacts, based on artifacts
      
      created in preceding phases (e.g. global model or service contracts/designs).
    </para>
    <para>
      To ensure that the services continue to conform to the artifacts defined in the previous
      
      phases, the tools perform conformance checking between the service implementation and
      
      the existing architecture/design artifacts. This is not possible with all implementation
      
      languages - they must provide the means to extract the communication structure for
      
      comparison.
    </para>
    <para>
      The following sections explain how the generation and conformance checking can be achieved
      
      for the WS-BPEL implementation language.
    </para>
    <section id="sid-3735783">
      
      <title>BPEL</title>
      <para>
        This tools include a capability to generate a service implementation, for a participant in a choreography,
        
        using WS-BPEL. A completed version of the
        <emphasis role="italics">PurchasingGoods</emphasis>
        example can be
        
        found in the samples directory (which can be imported into Eclipse).
      </para>
      <para>
        However if you wish to generate the example from scratch, the follow the instructions in this section.
        
        More information about how to use this feature can be found in the User Guide.
      </para>
      <section id="sid-3735783_WS-BPEL-GeneratingWSBPELbasedServices">
        
        <title>Generating WS-BPEL based Services</title>
        <para>
          When a choreography description has been created, it is possible to generate a BPEL Process (and associated
          
          WSDL files and deployment descriptor) for each of the participants defined within the choreography.
          
          To try this out, select the
          <emphasis role="italics">Savara-&gt;Generate-&gt;Service</emphasis>
          menu item from the popup menu
          
          associated with the
          <code>PurchaseGoods.cdm</code>
          .
        </para>
        <para>
          <figure>
<title>TODO InformalFigure image title empty</title>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="author/download/attachments/3735783/GenerateServiceMenu.png" width="3in"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
        </para>
        <para>
          This will display a dialog listing the possible services that can be generated from this choreography,
          
          with a proposed Eclipse project name, and the option to select a
          
          service type (in this case BPEL).
        </para>
        <para>
          <figure>
<title>TODO InformalFigure image title empty</title>
            <mediaobject>
              <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="author/download/attachments/3735783/GenerateService.png" width="5in"/>
              </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
          </figure>
        </para>
        <para>
          Press the 'Ok' button and this will create a single a BPEL project for the
          <emphasis role="italics">Store</emphasis>
          and
          
          <emphasis role="italics">CreditAgency</emphasis>
          participants.
        </para>
        <para>
          Each project will contain a single
          <code>bpel</code>
          folder containing the WS-BPEL process
          
          definition for the participant, a list of relevant WSDL files and a deployment descriptor file
          
          for use with RiftSaw. However the WS-BPEL and WSDL files are standard, so can be deployed to any
          
          WS-BPEL 2.0 compliant engine.
        </para>
      </section>
      <section id="sid-3735783_WS-BPEL-Addingimplementationdetails">
        
        <title>Adding implementation details</title>
        <para>
          The generated BPEL processes and deployment descriptors are incomplete, due to
          
          lack of implementation details in the choreography description. The choreography
          
          simply represents the externally observable interactions between the parties,
          
          and therefore cannot provide internal implementation details.
        </para>
        <para>
          Therefore a completed version of the deployment descriptor and BPEL process files,
          
          for both the creditAgency and store participants, can be found in the
          
          <emphasis role="italics">purchasing</emphasis>
          example's
          <code>completed/bpel</code>
          folder.
        </para>
        <para>
          To highlight the differences between the original generated version, and the completed
          
          version, simply select both files and use the
          <emphasis role="italics">Compare With-&gt;Each Other</emphasis>
          
          menu item.
        </para>
      </section>
    </section>
  </chapter>
